

Sebastian Franco Holguin

Email:Franco9490@gmail.com Celular: +57 3174367203

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastianfrancoholguin/

Profile

I am an Industrial Engineer focused on the commercial area and project management, with experience in sales of technological infrastructure services in the telecommunications industry. I focus on the development of large-scale, highly complex projects, mitigating risks and capitalizing on opportunities that generate value for both clients and the company.

I specialize in promoting business development, standing out in organic growth and generating new opportunities related to budget optimization, providing personalized attention, consolidating relationships of trust with clients, through the identification and satisfaction of their needs.

Experience

Customer Care and Sales Representative August 2023- Current

Asurion, Bogotá.

- Exceptional customer service and remote support for customer issue resolution.
- Commercial management through upsell building a relationship with the client, identifying the solution that satisfies their needs through the corresponding product or service.

Service Solution Bidding Engineer June 2022 – July 2023

Huawei Technologies Colombia by People Solution, Bogotá.

- Promote the service portfolio directly with the prospects and customers.
- Develop commercial proposals and estimates of business opportunities.
- Execute sales funnel for RFI/RFP, including pre-sales processes.
- Manage B2B service solutions integrating PMO, NTD to define costs per client/opportunity.
- Work as a team with Product Management on requests for functionalities and technical solutions.

Achievements:

- Sales of more than 3.7 MUSD in telecommunications tech solutions.
- Development of end to end swap project to update SDH technology to OTN.

Project Controller Manager March 2021 – June 2022

Huawei Technologies Colombia by SERDAN, Bogotá

- Customer management (Huawei-CLARO)
- Planning and control of portfolio, revenue and billing.
- Implementation, control and monitoring of MBB TLF deployment-delivery.
- •Management of purchase orders for materials and supplies at the national level. Achievements:
- End to End project development "master plan" macro FTTX project.

Warehouse Manager June 2020 – March 2021

Huawei Technologies Colombia by People Solution, Bogotá.

- Forecasting and assurance of storage and transportation operational capacity.
- Budgetary control of storage centers nationwide.
- Planning and implementation of the continuous improvement program.
- Development of business continuity plan.
- Standardization of reports, transportation and warehouse KPIs. Management of internal clients. Achievements:
- •Study of capacity and expansion of warehouses and logistics processes.
- •Location study and negotiation of a new supply center.
- •Implementation project for a new 3PL supplier (Development of tenders and BOQ according to technical requirements).

Transportation Analyst August 2019– June 2020

Huawei Technologies Colombia by ADECCO, Bogotá

- Programming and routing of vehicles nationwide for TLF client.
- Management of internal clients (Huawei Telefónica).
- Budget control of transportation/air imports.

Trade Marketing Trainee June 2018 - February 2019

HERO- HMCL Colombia, Villa Rica-Cauca

- Preparation of reports on promotional activities and analysis of tactics at points of sale.
- Support in the design, control and analysis of promotional actions focused on increasing traffic at points of sale and obtaining potential leads.
- Managed purchases and inventory control of POP material, guaranteeing availability at points of sale nationwide by rotation levels. Achievements:
- Development of commercial incentive plan.
- Savings on POP material purchases of 15%.

Education

- Industrial Engineering Universidad del Valle. 2014-2019
- Intensive English course "Cali open to work" focused on Customer Service. Comfenalco Valley. October 2021 December 2021.
- Diploma in Business Intelligence and Data Analysis. Valley University. October 2020 December 2020.
- Diploma in Strategic Marketing Techniques and Tactics. Development of commercial proposals. Structuring of the sales force. Channel sales strategies. Cali Chamber of Commerce. October 2015.

Curses

- Agile Team Management Course. July 2022
- SCRUM Professional Course. June 2022
- Advanced Internet Networking Course. June 2022
- Internet Computer Networking Course. June 2022
- Commercial Strategy B2B Course. June 2022
- WhatsApp Business Course. February 2022

- Technology Course for Managers and Directors. January 2022
- Software Engineering Fundamentals. November 2021

Skills

- Great interpersonal communication skills, analytical, proactive and innovative, achievement-oriented, professional with great teamwork and leadership skills.
- Excel: Professional and data analytics.
- Power BI: Professional, data visualization.
- English: Commercial and professional level.